PANAGIOTIS PAPADOMITSOS CURRICULUM VITÆ

388 Beale str.
San Francisco, CA94105
+1 (702) 358-4128
http://ezgr.net
https://github.com/priestjim
http://linkedin.com/in/priestjim

ELEVATOR PITCH

Systems and Software engineer specializing in conception, design and implementation of distributed applications and their supporting infrastructures running on **GNU/Linux**, FreeBSD and Microsoft Windows operating systems with equal experience in leading and managing both development and operations-oriented teams.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Phlock Inc. :: San Francisco, California :: www.phlock.io

2015 - now

Co-Founder / CTO

- Responsible for the conception, development and implementation of the infrastructure supporting the Phlock mobile apps and web platform, the project's website and parts of the web application.
- Designed and developed the project's backend service in Erlang and C, focusing on superior image operations and user experience.
- **Tags**: AWS, Chef, Splunk, PostgreSQL, NGINX, Lua, Erlang, GraphicsMagick, C, AngularJS, Gulp

Splunk Inc. :: San Francisco, California :: <u>www.splunk.com</u>

2013 – now

Head of Mobile Intelligence Cloud

- **⊃** Responsible for the conception, development and implementation of the Cloud infrastructure supporting the Mobile Intelligence product.
- Development Lead on a family of Erlang-based projects that receive and process more than 150.000 regs/sec from mobile devices all over the world. Holder of a total of 4 patents related to those projects.
- **⊃** Evaluated and designed the software and the infrastructure for the company-wide private container cloud solution based on Kubernetes, Swarm, Docker, Python and Go.
- **⊃** Team lead for the Infrastructure Automation, CI/CD, Operations and Erlang Development teams, collectively managing 4 direct reports, supporting the Cloud aspect of 3 different high profile products.
- **Tags**: AWS, Google AppEngine, Chef, Ansible, Graphite, Grafana, Splunk, Jenkins, Bamboo, Kubernetes, Docker, Erlana, Elixir, Go. Git/Stash

BugSense Inc. :: San Francisco, California :: www.bugsense.com

2012 - 2013

Head of Infrastructure

- **⊃** Responsible for the design and implementation of the company's cloud infrastructure and various supporting services.
- **⊃** Development Lead of the Erlang/C/Lisp in-memory streaming database that supports the company's "Insight Boxes" analytics offering.
- → Member of the team that led to the successful acquisition of BugSense Inc. by Splunk Inc. on September 2013.
- **Tags**: AWS, Google AppEngine, Windows Azure, Chef, Percona MySQL, JIRA, Memcached, Redis, uWSGI, NGINX, Lua, PHP-FPM, Sinatra, Celery, RabbitMQ, Sensu, Ganglia, Mercurial, Git, Python, Ruby, Erlang, C, PHP, ElasticSearch, Logstash, Graphite, Riemann, LXC/Docker, Jenkins

dnHost Web Hosting Agency :: Athens, Greece :: www.dnhost.gr

Director of Engineering

2009 – 2012

- Responsible for the design and implementation of the company's cloud infrastructure and services.
- ⇒ R&D department lead developer.
- **Tags**: Rackspace Cloud, VMWare vSphere, Parallels Virtuozzo, KVM, IPv6, Percona MySQL, Memcached, Redis, Apache, OpenVPN, Asterisk, Bind, Litespeed, Tomcat, NGINX, PHP-FPM, Postfix, Zabbix, Ganglia, SpamAssassin, PHP, HTML5, CSS3, Smarty, CodeIgniter, Yii Framework, XML-RPC/SOAP, jQuery, Subversion, Cisco Catalyst, Windows Server, IIS 7.5, ASP.NET, SmarterMail, R1Soft CDP

Hellenic Lifeguard Academy :: Athens, Greece :: www.enak.gr

2005 - 2006 & 2007 - 2009

IT Director

- Responsible for the design, management and maintenance of company's network and system infrastructure.
- **Solution** Responsible for the company's online presence.
- **Tags**: XHTML, CSS2, MySQL, PHP, Joomla, Asterisk, Active Directory, Citrix XenServer, KVM, DansGuardian, OpenVPN

Wanderful Solutions L.T.D. :: Athens, Greece :: www.wanderful.gr

2006 - 2007

IT Solutions Engineer

- **⊃** Lead IT Solutions engineer, responsible for the design, implementation and support of small and medium scale internetworked applications and infrastructure.
- **Tags**: XHTML, CSS2, Asterisk, Windows Server, Active Directory, Microsoft Exchange Server, Borland Delphi

Operating Systems Laboratory, T.E.I. of Piraeus :: Athens, Greece :: www.teipir.gr

2002 - 2004

System & Network Administrator

- Responsible for the management and maintenance of the laboratory's server farm and application infrastructure.
- **⊃ Tags**: XHTML, CSS2, FreeBSD, IPFilter, SunRay Terminals

Interactive Telecom S.A. :: Athens, Greece

2000 - 2002

System & Network Administrator

- Responsible for the management and maintenance of the company's local computer network.
- **Tags**: Microsoft Windows Networking, Windows 2000 Server

EDUCATION

Technological Educational Institute of Piraeus

2002 - 2012

Department of Electronic Computer Systems and Information Technology

BSc in Electronic Computer Systems Engineering, GPA 7.45/10.0

Thesis subject: Statistical calculation of xDSL/ATM line parameters using online GIS systems

Honors: Admission scholarship, after achieving 6th place in admission order.

TALKS

Erlang Factory SF Bay 2016, San Francisco

March 10th, 2016

Subject: Improving RPC calls in Erlang and Elixir

ErLounge Erlang Meetup, San Francisco

April 14th, 2014

Subject: Introducing the Cloud Data Collector for IoT

OpenFest F/OSS Symposium, T.E.I. of Piraeus

December 14th to 15th, 2002

Subject: Design and implementation of a university's lab IT infrastructure using Free and Open Source Software.

SEMINARS

Erlang Factory SF San Francisco, California

2014-2016

EuRuKo 2013 Badminton Theater, Athens

May 2013

Install, configure and manage VMWare vSphere 4.1 Performance V.A.D.

December 2010

HP Certified Professional Hewlett-Packard Hellas

January - March 2007

OpenFest F/OSS Symposium

T.E.I. of Piraeus, Athens

December 14^{th} to 15^{th} , 2002

GRNet F/OSS Symposium Holiday Inn Hotel, Athens

June 27th, 2002

OTHER PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

Scientific associate for Packt Publishing, recently reviewed "Mastering Chef" by Mayank Joshi.

- Member of the Athens Wireless Metropolitan Network (A.W.M.N.) with Node ID #4813.
- Regular speaker at the San Francisco Erlang meetup.

LANGUAGE CERTIFICATIONS

English Mother-tongue fluency in both written and oral level.

Certifications Certificate of Proficiency in English, University of Cambridge

French Fluent in both written and oral level.

Certifications IFA DELF 2

Greek Mother-tongue fluency in both written and oral level.

PERSONAL INTERESTS

Astronomy, literature, photography, fingerstyle guitar, ice hockey, snowboarding.